[Music]
Hello friends,
I am Sumit Bhandari, welcome to healthinsurance.com.
Today's topic is Your Question Our
Answers. So let's take the first question.
Nowadays, we are getting a lot of queries regarding this.
Tell us from your side, what is your
rating for ICS Lombard's new plan Elevate. Or how does the
feature of unlimited savings
in this plan actually work? Or what are its
benefits or disadvantages? Okay,
see, whenever we review any company's product,
normally I don't do it much,
but just for my clients,
when we look at that policy, we
look at three main factors in it. How is the company, that is,
how is the process system of the company? In that case, it is a very good company. The
second aspect that comes up is that for
how many benefits has this product been
made? Okay, how was it made for other benefits?
See, maximum people who
take health insurance policy have to pay
its premium, why
maximum people  Only those who belong to middle class families
need these policies. When
such a person takes a policy, then naturally, if
I have to propose a policy to a client, then
I first do its cost benefit
analysis. The amount of money that
this person will spend in this policy for the whole life,
right? Depending on various factors, right? Is it worth that much
or does it have
that much value or not? So,
from that aspect, if I look at this policy, I
find the policy quite expensive. I am
not going into too much detail about what it has
in it. So,
suppose there is Health Advantage in IC Labad, there is
Max product, there are three-four
more products and there is Elevate. So, if
a client of mine has sworn that he has to
take a policy of IC Labad only, then will
I recommend this plan to anyone? There are very less
chances that it may not meet my philosophy. It does make this
policy bad. It is a good policy, it is a fine policy,
but the way I
tell someone, my criteria is that  The
criteria is value for
money. Is the amount of money invested in it worth the
money you are getting? In that
case, I find many flaws in the policy.
Okay, now I am talking on the basis of that criteria. So, is it a
value for money product? If no, then will
I recommend it to anyone? There are very less
chances that I will recommend it to anyone. But it does make this
policy bad. Who am I to
tell the pros and cons of a policy?
My job is as a consultant. When I have to
tell someone, I have to do its cost-benefit
analysis. What is the branding of the company?
What has been the company's record of increasing premiums in the last 20 years? Are the
features of this policy
really that powerful or not? Fourth,
what is the advertising cost of this company? Fifth,
what is the incentive structure of this company?
I have to look at it from the consumer's perspective based on many factors.
No, I am repeating myself. I am
not saying anything about the policy. I have to
recommend anyone. I will
not recommend most of the time. Okay, yes.  Our
clients, our assisting clients,
ask us, so we tell them logically that
buy it for this reason or don't
buy it for that reason, but I what find it a very fantastic
value for money product. Well, the third
reason behind this is that the company
created a concept to launch this policy,
which is called I what use object word in
which the company says that we will pay whatever claim you have,
this is a very good
concept, we will analyze it,
how will we do the analysis, if suppose someone has
taken a policy of 5 lakhs, then he has a claim of 50 lakhs once
in his life, then this
policy will pay him, it will definitely pay, what will happen, it is
okay, the customer has
benefited a lot, but lakhs of
people who had taken a policy of only 5 lakhs, the
company
collected crores of rupees from them,
sold policies to thousands of people, collected 20, 303 thousand from them
and told them that this is a policy of 5 lakhs,
this is a policy of 10 lakhs, we will help
you in marketing for this.  Competing will
give such a high premium and will give a feature that if any
such claim comes which is very high then
we will pay it, so suppose if someone's
claim comes for 50 lakhs then the company paid it and
that customer benefited or
suppose if someone's claim came for 20 lakhs then that
customer definitely benefited but
instead of 5 lakhs, he was given a claim of 20 lakhs,
that means 15 lakhs went out of the company's pocket, the
second and first claim was that he had taken a policy for 5 lakhs
and when a claim of 50 lakhs came then the
company paid 45 lakhs, brother, the company will
recover the claim of 45 lakhs and the extra 15 lakhs given, that is 6 lakh rupees
from its own pocket, what do you say,
now understand the matter, so
suppose those who did not take the claim, their policy was of 00,
their premium will become 24-25000, it may become
00 because in such a situation I am talking about only two
claims, one was of 45 lakhs
in excess and  If at least one person
got more than 15 lakhs, then this 6 lakhs would have gone out of the company
and suppose the company has received a lot of
claims these days whose claims are of 5
lakhs, so what is the value, suppose you had
taken a policy of 10 lakhs, the
claim of 25 lakhs which has gone above 15 lakhs,
from whose pocket will this be recovered, the rest of the
policy holders and this brother,
both of whom will have the claim, they will happily pay it
but the company will not pay it from its pocket, so
when such a feature is there, I do
not believe much in such features,
but I am talking rationally, I am
talking in terms of mathematics, finance and commerce, that
suppose many people got such
claims and the company sold five policies of 10 lakhs each
and
collected money of 100 crores, but the
outgo of that became 125 crores
because the company said that we will give
you unlimited type of claim once, no matter how much
you have.  Take a look at the summaries, there are a
very minute fraction of people
who will benefit from this, but the burden of this will fall on the
rest of the people. So,
suppose you
live in a society, today all the
people in the society are demanding that
a new generator set be installed in our society so that we
get a good power supply, so your
association says, okay, we will do it, so
next time,
suppose you are paying Rs. 000 as maintenance,
from next time, you will get Rs. 000 or for one or two years, the
company, your association, will
suddenly ask you Rs. 000, friend, I do
n't even live here, okay, why did they increase mine?
Many people had paid rent, they did
not get much benefit from that electricity,
so some people definitely benefited,
but the burden of this will have to be borne by the rest of the people, so
when the society installs a
generator worth Rs. 10 lakh or Rs. 20 lakh, then
who will bear its cost,
all the people will bear it, so whenever you see,
what I basically want to say is  I mean, look, there are
many such products in the market in
which higher insurance is available at a nominal premium.
If you like this product
and you like it only because you get
unlimited cover in it, then
I will just give you an example.
What happened is a test on
which you check whether
this policy will work properly in this case or
not. Suppose today there is a brother who
took a policy of 5 lakhs,
ICU Loba Elevate, and after a few years
he gets cancer, his claim came for
2 lakhs, 25 lakhs. He got the claim and is
very happy, so he will benefit.
Now after some time the premium will increase,
but when someone gets cancer,
naturally his income will also be affected
because he will not be able to go to his job or business for a few months,
so there will be financial
stress, that was bound to happen anyway.
Now suppose, next year or
after a year or two, if he gets cancer again, will
he get 25 lakhs or not,
or will he  10 years because he got cancer,
after getting cancer you
cannot even increase the sum assured, okay, so I am giving you a hint,
understand this thing, if you are not able to understand then
sit with your agent and
tell him this example that this brother is saying this here,
explain to him in which case I am getting benefit
and in the long term, if someone gets
cancer and lives for the next 40 years, then will he be able to
survive in that sum, will he not be able to, so understand the
thing, do not be greedy, do not
go on that feature, okay,
look for such products in the market, let us
assume that the product is
very popular in the market, okay, when a
popular, very popular product is the
first thing, a lot of advertisement has been done behind it,
number two, when people start telling you again and again
that buy an elevator, elevator,
then think that they are going to get a lot of benefit from selling it, only then
someone praises someone,
okay, whatever you see, you pay money to the reviews of films and get them to say something.
So, there is a similar thing in health insurance.
I am saying the same thing again. It is
not that this product is bad, but you
cannot check it.
This new product has just been launched.
What contests has the company run in it that if you
sell so much, you will get so much.
Naturally, this policy is more expensive than other ICICI policies,
so that means the commission is also
going to the agent. Okay, thirdly, the
financial influencers are repeatedly saying that
this is a great product,
brother, look here I am telling you with folded hands,
I am not praising myself,
but I think most of the people who are
talking about this have not even seen any claims in their life. Okay,
what does a claim mean? Have you
ever bought a policy for a person at the age of 55,
today he is 70 years old, you know his pain,
what
types of claims come, so when you do
not have practical experience, it is
very easy to say that this product has
this and that, buy it in this way. Okay, so
I am very much against this policy.  I will
not recommend it. My thinking is that as per the
benefit of the client, I feel that there is a
superior product available than this. I will
say again that this product is not bad
but as per my thinking I would take it a very
high rated product. So let's
take the second question. Okay,
secondly this brother has a question that I
forgot to tell you that we bought a policy.
See, many people get to
know about this thing by watching our videos etc.
This is the question of this brother that
10 years ago he was detected with BP,
so he took medicine for it for some time
and after taking some medicine,
he stopped the medicine after some time. After a year when
he took the policy, he had told his agent about it.
I will not take the name of the company.
9 years ago when he took the policy, he had
told in it. Now
today he came and found out that his agent had
not told the company. Okay, so he has
asked his question in very detail. So
his question is that will this
information cause me any loss? Will it be 100%
legal and  In technical terms, we would
say that a fraud has taken place. Look,
you are a very honest person, a spiritual
person, a religious person, never doing any harm to anyone.
You told your agent honestly as well. If the
agent did not inform him further, then
understand that there is a problem, can
it be resolved? It can be
resolved, it depends on the
intention of your company. You can talk to them and get
it resolved through communication. They may accept it, they
may even cancel your policy, a 9-year-old
policy. This is the company's
decision, the company knows, it is the company's job, they will
look into it. There are two technical things, if
some correction is to be done in this, that
depends on your company whether it will cancel
it or not. Secondly, is this a
mistake? It is a very serious mistake, right? So,
in short, a very serious mistake has been made, right? Okay.
Next question, is there any question? Clearly,
his language was a bit rough,
in it he said that you are from
SGFC or Optima Secure.
Why don't you recommend this policy, okay, I am
saying it in very simple language
brother, I feel so, okay, I will
not talk about much technicality, I am very
practical, I feel that most of the people who have taken SDFC Ergo
Optimus policy,
majority of the people, you know, a
very high
percentage, will have to close this policy in the coming time,
okay, they will
not be able to run it, the policy will become so expensive,
okay, I am not saying here
that SDFC is not a company, Optimus
Secure is not a good product, it has everything,
I am saying that it is very good, it is a class
five star product, I will recommend it to anyone, not
99.99%, not 100%, I will not recommend this policy to anyone
because in very simple language, I
feel that this policy will be very costly for the people who will come, whatever
you want brother, no matter how much you earn, you will
not be able to run this policy, you can impose as many
conditions as you want, you do not know what this
policy is, okay, so on what basis am I
refusing, because it will become so expensive in the coming time,
you will not run it at all  If you find it,
what is the reason for it? I
can tell you in brief right now. The costing is very
high. The policy is very expensive. You won't be able to afford the high rates.
If you have the
courage, then check it yourself. Okay, you will
talk to me in rude language. It doesn't matter to me. Whatever
you say is fine. I have nothing to do
with the company. I am
busy with my own business. Okay, let's take one final
question.
Some time back, the government said that
you should reduce the waiting period for pre-assisted diseases from 4
years to 3 years. Did it have any practical effect? ​​It has
definitely come. New India has
increased the rates by 10%. New India has increased the rates by 10%.
However, New India is such a
company, that is, if I talk from 2002
till now, okay, this is a very sudden
premium jump. Normally, they have never increased the premium by doing such a jump randomly
in history.
Its
structure of increasing the premium is different. The model is different. It used to
increase it in that way.
Why did the government increase the premium by 10% suddenly?  The IID
said that the waiting period for pre-assisting was five years, make
it three years. I do
n't see any benefit of even one rupee in this to the
customer. I have shouted in my old videos that
this benefit will
harm the customer, will there be any loss
or what do you mean what was the government thinking,
what will be the benefit in this, I have a BP
problem, I bought a BP policy today, the
company told me that after three years,
after four years
we will cover any BP claim, okay, I will
wait for four years. Now the government said, no
brother, we have changed it, earlier you had to
cover it after four years, now we will
cover it after nine years, okay, so I got a little
happy, then the very next year when I had to
renew the policy, my
premium was increased by 10, I
said friend, you have suddenly increased the premium
and said sir, we have given you the benefit,
I said I did not ask
you for it, you know, so what happens is that when whatever
type of reforms are coming,
whatever formulas are coming in the industry
Look, that will make me open my mouth.
This company is making IID changes
directly, indirectly.
I would say that the customer is
not getting any benefit from it. It is very clear. The
real benefit that he should have got was
simplification of the policy so that his
pocket gets some relief in any way.
You have made a good sacrifice. Many people had
policies in operation. A person
took it in 2010. The waiting period for pre-assisting in his policy was
4 years. He had a
problem of BP and sugar. He was supposed to get that cover after 4 years.
Okay, now that 4-year waiting
period for him is over today
because you have reduced the 4-year waiting period in his policy to 3 years. Or make it
3 years for all. Brother, he has suffered a
loss by sitting idle. First he
took a waiting period of 4 years and today you have increased his
waiting period. It does not matter to him
because his policy is 14 years old.
What difference will it make to him? But he has been
fined 10 times more for sitting idle.
Do it, okay, so look, I
request the government with folded hands or
any other
authorities to bring
reforms in the health insurance industry,
but bring it in such a way that the customer's
money has to be paid, first the middle class is
dead, how much will you
spare them, okay, so that you have
directly or indirectly forced them to pay
10% of the money directly into the hands of the companies,
whose salary has increased so much, you have increased his premium by 10% while sitting, basically,
and all the other
companies will increase it, okay, if you
can, then take such a step that the
premium of my consumer, my own policy remains stable, at least it does not increase too
much, you are increasing it while sitting,
secondly, if you have to do something, if you have a
good intention to do something, then regulate the hospitals,
which hospital is it, see today, I am clearly
saying that because of this
our videos get suppressed, the channels also get
blocked because of this, but there are two things,
today you look at any hospital,
what hospital is open?  In any city, a
hospital is opened at such a place that it is an
allocated place, it is a
no profit no loss thing and a
hospital, understand this thing, school and
hospital, these two things are such no profit
no loss industries, which hospital chain is
not making profit of crores of rupees in every quarter today, insurance
for what, insurance is
this business that companies have to earn profit of
crores of rupees, oh brother, middle
class people pay money from their pocket,
which company's, today's date, every
company is making a profit of 1000-2000 crore rupees, they are
earning a lot, they have to set up a
factory, you will
bring a claim portal now, that will also increase the claim rejection of the company,
okay, so if someone has the
intention to do it, then grab the neck of the hospitals, for the
treatment which is under one lakh rupees,
they are charging 5 lakhs, Happa
filter is above the name of this filter,
consultant, you see, the government, I will pin
point you, the government has created a concept
that your hospital's  There is an expense,
suppose today you need to get a knee
replacement done or your state suppose
you need to get a stent inserted, today the
cost of getting a stent inserted, the government said that
no brother, it is costing too much, to
reduce it you should
increase the costing of the stent, has anyone gone and checked,
I am saying this with a lot of bitterness, has
anyone gone and checked whether the cost
of the stent
operation, angioplasty or whatever you
call it, has reduced in the hospital, it has
not reduced at all, it has not reduced, not
how much, they have taken the
stent from here and
increased it on the other side, they have increased their expenses
even today they are spending on the same number of people, right,
now this is the kind of work, only
God knows how it will be done by the bureaucracy, so come on, if
any of you have any question,
want to ask any kind of
question, you can whatsapp us on
whatsapp.com, we have many articles,
they are on our website, on the blog,
healthirens.com, go there, if
any of you ever  If there is a
claim issue, then our
platform is open for you. Come and
we will do a live session. We will discuss about
your claim. That is, if there has been a
huge loss in your claim, then
you can share your experience and
why we will try to resolve it
so that many people can understand
what is the problem in this claim. Look, this is the health
insurance industry, it is a service industry. There are
many problems in it. It is
not an easy task, okay, but we have to understand it
so that we make minimum mistakes and so that
tomorrow when we need it, we get the claim.
Okay, so yes, all of you took the
time to watch this video.
Thank you very much. If anyone wants a
paid consultation, you can contact us
or you can go to our website and
book the package. Our minimum fee
is Rs. 699. And if you have any kind of
suggestion, then you can email us.
Thank you very much for taking the time to watch this video. Jai Jai Shri
Radhe